Guide to the Cass Gilbert Collection 1883-1952 (Bulk 1900-1934 ) PR 21
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Cass Gilbert Collection
1883-1952
PR 21
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
380.0 Linear feet (696 boxes, 444 bound volumes)
The Cass Gilbert Collection contains the professional and personal papers of the architect Cass Gilbert. This includes information on his architectural projects, professional affliations, and personal business. This finding aid does not include information on his architectural drawings.
Provenance
Gift of Cass Gilbert Jr. and Emily Gilbert, 1956 and 1957.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to thirty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Biographical Note
Cass Gilbert was born on November 24, 1859 in Zanesville, Ohio to Samuel Augustus Gilbert and Elizabeth Fulton Wheeler Gilbert. The family moved to St. Paul Minnesota in 1868, and in 1878 Gilbert went to study architecture at Massachusetts Institute of Technology. After traveling and studying in Europe, he joined the New York office of McKim, Mead & White in 1880. In 1882, he was sent to St. Paul to open a branch office for McKim, Mead & White and to oversee the building of depots, terminals, and hotels for the Northern Pacific Railroad. Within two years, the office collapsed and Gilbert formed a partnership with James Knox Taylor in St. Paul that lasted until 1892. Gilbert produced churches and houses in Minnesota and was a recognized architect when he won a competition to design the Minnesota State Capitol in 1895.
In 1899, Gilbert returned to New York City and received a number of significant commissions. He won a competition to design the United States Custom House (1901-1907) and designed the 24 storied building at 90 West Street (1905-1907) in Manhattan. From 1911-1913, Gilbert worked on the Woolworth Building. At 55 stories tall, it was the tallest building in the world from 1913 to 1930 and became one of Gilbert's most famous designs. Other buildings in New York designed by Gilbert include the New York Life Insurance Company Building (1925-1928) and the US Courthouse (1936), which was completed after his death. Gilbert also completed designs for the George Washington Memorial Bridge (1927-1931) that proved to be too expensive and were never used.
Gilbert also became known for his work on the Art Building in the Louisiana Purchase Exposition in 1904 which eventually became the St. Louis Art Museum. He also designed the St. Louis Public Library (1907-1912) and the Detroit Public Library (1913-1921). His work in Washington D.C. included the US Treasury Annex (1918-1919), the US Chamber of Commerce (1924-1925), and the US Supreme Court Building (1933-1935).
Gilbert was active in art and architectural organizations. He was appointed by President Theodore Roosevelt as chairman of the Council of Fine Arts. He was made a member of the Commission of Fine Arts by President Taft and reappointed to the post by President Woodrow Wilson. He was a long time member of the American Institute of Architects and served as its president from 1908-1909. In 1919 he resigned his membership from the AIA after disputes with the leadership of the organization. He was also a long time member of the National Academy of Design and served as its president from 1926-1932. He also served as a member of the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
Gilbert was recognized in America and abroad for his architectural work. He received honorary degrees from the University of Michigan, Oberlin College, and Middlebury College and was awarded the Society of Art and Sciences Gold Medal Award in 1930. In Europe, he was made an honorary member of the Agricultural Society of the University of Liverpool and an honorary foreign member of the Royal Academy of Arts. He was also decorated with the French Legion of Honor.
In 1887, Gilbert married Julia Tappan Finch, the daughter of a wealthy attorney from Milwaukee. Together they had three children: Cass Gilbert Jr., Emily Finch, and Julia Swift who became the wife of Charles Morgan Post. The family owned many properties including places in Manhattan and Connecticut. Gilbert was active in various social clubs including the Century Club and the Union Club. Gilbert died on vacation in Brockenhurst, England in 1934 at the age of 75. Cass Gilbert Jr. worked as an architect in his father's office and finished many of the office's projects after his death.
Scope and Content Note
The Cass Gilbert Collection spans the period from 1883-1952 (bulk 1900-1934) and contains professional and personal papers relating to the architect Cass Gilbert. This finding aid does not include information on the architectural drawings of Cass Gilbert. Most of this collection consists of files related to his numerous architectural projects. These files contain materials related to projects that he completed as well as projects that he worked on but did not complete. The collection also documents his extensive work in art and architectural associations. His personal papers mainly relate to personal business and some family letters are included. The arrangement attempts to adhere to Gilbert's filing system as closely as possible. See the Print Room at the New-York Historical Society for a detailed box and folder listing for the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into nine series:
Series 1: Project Files
Series 2: Office Files
Series 3: Professional Organizations
Series 4: Personal Files
Series 5: Lantern Slides
Series 6: Record Book of Drawings
Series 7: Scrapbooks
Series 8: Metal Printing Plates
Series 9: European Sketchbooks
Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections
The Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections at the New-York Historical Society also holds the architectural drawings of many of Cass Gilbert's projects.
Photographs of many Cass Gilbert projects can be found in the Geographic File, PR20. A photograph of the dinner thrown by F.W. Woolworth in Cass Gilbert's honor can be found in the Portrait File, PR52, under Groups, Commercial, in Large Format. There is also a photograph of Cass Gilbert and his family in the Portrait File, PR 52, under "G" in Medium Format.
Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.); American Institute of Architects.; Aus, Gunvald.; Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936.; Burr, Stiles.; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America--Buildings.; Comstock, Louis K. (Louis Kossuth), 1865-1962.; Detroit Public Library-- Buildings.; French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931.; George A. Fuller Company.; Gilbert, Cass, b. 1894.; Gilbert, Charles.; Gilbert, Julia Finch, 1862-1952.; Gilbert, Samuel.; Hedden Construction Co.; James Stewart and Company.; Minnesota State Capitol (Saint Paul, Minn.: 1883-1905); National Academy of Design (U.S.); New York Insurance Company Building.; Olmstead, F. H.; Rockart, John R., 1872?-1951.; St. Louis Art Museum.; Thompson-Starrett Co.; Turner Construction Company; United States. Commission of Fine Arts.; United States.--Dept. of the Treasury--Buildings.; United States.--Supreme Court--Buildings--Washington (D.C.); Webb, Aston, Sir, 1849-1930.; West Street Building (New York, N.Y.); Woolworth Building (New York, N.Y.); Agreements.; Architectural records.; Architecture--United States--19th century.; Bids.; Brochures.; Buildings--Connecticut.; Buildings--Minnesota.; Buildings--New Jersey.; Buildings--New York (State); Cashbooks.; Clippings.; Commercial buildings--United States.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Drawings.; Dwellings--United States.; Financial statements.; Floor plans.; Historic buildings--United States.; Lantern slides.; Ledgers.; Letter books.; Memorandums.; New York (N.Y.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Notes.; Office buildings--United States.; Payroll records.; Photographs.; Printing plates.; Public buildings--United States.; Railroad stations--United States.; Renderings.; Reports.; Scrapbooks.; Sketchbooks.; Sketches.; Skyscrapers--United States.; Specifications.; Washington (D.C.)--Buildings, structures, etc.
- Series I. Project Files
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes material related to Cass Gilbert's architectural projects. Most of the projects are buildings built by Gilbert. However the files also include information on projects he competed for but did not receive or are documents regarding a particular subject or a business. This series represents the bulk of the collection.
  - Subseries I: Foldered Material
    This subseries contains the box and foldered material regarding Cass Gilbert projects. The material has been filed alphabetically by project and then by the project number assigned by Gilbert's office. Gilbert also designated material within the project files by type. Thus, the project files are also divided by type of material. The types of material include Preliminary Correspondence, Correspondence, Memoranda/Notes, Specifications, Bid Documents, Proposals, Reports, Contracts/Agreements, Financial Statements (includes Requisitions), Change Orders, Drawings, Photographs, etc.
    - Abbott Apartment Building (Milwaukee, WI), 1890 (Box 1)
    - Adams Stable (112 East 52nd Street, NY, NY), 1900-1910 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY), 1928-1934 (Box 1-5)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ), 1902-1930 (Box 5-12)
    - American Terra Cotta and Ceramic Company, 1901 (Box 12)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR), 1901-1930 (Box 13-25)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA), 1919-1920 (Box 26-30)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY), 1913-1930 (Box 30-42)
    - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 1910 (Box 42)
    - Beverly Public Library (Beverley, MA), 1905-1919 (Box 42-44)
    - Brazer Building (Boston, MA), 1896, 1901 (Box 44)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT), 1914-1934 (Box 45-50)
    - E.C. Bridgman (Publisher and Mounter), 1901-1902 (Box 50)
    - Broad Street Property Development (New York, NY), 1902 (Box 50)
    - Broadway Chambers Building (New York, NY), 1899-1926 (Box 51-53)
    - Brooklyn Army Terminal (see United States Army Supply Base)
    - Brooklyn Rapid Transit, 1903 (Box 53)
    - Brunswick School (Greenwich, CT), 1933 (Box 53)
    - Bureau of the American Republics (Washington, DC), 1903 (Box 53)
    - Burnham & Co. Architects, 1903-1904 (Box 53)
    - Alexander Sterling Calder, 1904 (Box 54)
    - Camden County Building Committee (Camden, NJ), 1902-1903 (Box 54)
    - Capitol Building (Havana, Cuba), 1903-1904 (Box 54)
    - Capitol Improvement Commission (Madison, WI), 1903-1904 (Box 54)
    - Carnegie Library (St. Paul, MN), 1903 (Box 54)
    - Carpenters' Letters, 1901-1902 (Box 54)
    - Castaigne Drawings, 1904 (Box 54)
    - Charleston Public Library (Charleston, NC), 1924-1925 (Box 54)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT), 1916-1932 (Box 54-61)
    - Chase Memorial Dispensary (Waterbury, CT), 1923-1924 (Box 61-62)
    - The Chronicle Company, 1901 (Box 62)
    - Cleveland, Ralph D., 1901 (Box 62)
    - Continental National Bank of Chicago (Chicago, IL), 1902 (Box 62)
    - Criterion Club Building Committee, 1903 (Box 62)
    - Day, Frank Miles, 1902-1905 (Box 62)
    - Dayton Avenue Presbyterian Church (St. Paul, MN), 1902-1912 (Box 62)
    - De Laittre, John (His residence), 1905 (Box 63)
    - Delmonico Site Hotel Project (Broadway, 5th Avenue and 26th Street, NY, NY), 1900-1901 (Box 63)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI), 1913-1933 (Box 63-75)
    - Elwere, Edwin (Curator of Sculpture, Metropolitan Museum of Art), 1902 (Box 75)
    - Endicott Building (St. Paul, MN), 1901-1916 (Box 75-76)
    - Endicott Building -Rantoul portion (St. Paul, MN), 1902 (Box 76)
    - Essex Building (St. Paul), 1905-1906 (Box 76)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ), 1901-1929 (Box 76-91)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN), 1919-1928 (Box 92-109)
    - 15-17 East 40th Street (New York, NY), 1916-1917 (Box 109)
    - Fifth Avenue and 72nd Street Apartment (New York, NY), 1911 (Box 109)
    - First Division Memorial (Washington, D.C), 1921-1934 (Box 110-112)
    - Floranada Club (Palm Beach, Florida), 1925-1934 (Box 113)
    - G. Fox and Co. Department Store (Hartford, CT), 1917-1932 (Box 113-114)
    - George Junior Republic School (Litchfield, CT), 1915-1917 (Box 114)
    - Grace Graves Memory Tablet (Duluth, MN), 1904-1905 (Box 114)
    - George Washington Bridge (see Hudson River Bridge)
    - Grand Island Bridge (see Niagara Frontier Bridge)
    - John L. Hamilton & Sons, 1902 (Box 114)
    - Helena Hotel (Helena, MT), 1912-1915 (Box 114)
    - Hodges and Nichols Building (Duluth, MN), 1900-1904 (Box 115-116)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT), 1914-1930 (Box 116-126)
    - Hotel on C&O Railroad (Lexington, KY), 1904 (Box 126)
    - Hudson River Bridge (Hudson River, NY), 1925-1933 (Box 126-130)
    - Illuminating Engineering Company, 1904 (Box 130)
    - Interzone Building (New York, NY), 1920-1934 (Box 130-134)
    - Ives Memorial Library (New Haven, CT), 1907-1932 (Box 134-139)
    - Jamaica Estates (Long Island, NY), 1908-1911 (Box 139-140)
    - James House (Greenwich, CT), 1931-1932 (Box 140)
    - Johnson Cement Coating, 1900-1901 (Box 140)
    - Kill Van Kull Bridge (Bayonne, NJ), 1926-1931 (Box 140)
    - Kinney Building (Newark, NJ), 1912-1930 (Box 140-149)
    - Le Clere, Francis, 1901 (Box 149)
    - Lincoln House (Waterbury, CT), 1916-1918 (Box 149)
    - Loney Tomb (Skaneateles, NY), 1900-1910 (Box 150)
    - Losey Memorial (La Crosse, WI), 1901 (Box 150)
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition (later the St. Louis Art Museum), 1901-1919 (Box 150-154)
    - Lyon Cottage (White Bear Lake, MN), Undated (Box 154)
    - Macey Office Furniture, 1901 (Box 154)
    - Madison High School (Madison, WI), 1903-1909 (Box 154-157)
    - Manhattan Press Clippings Bureau, 1901 (Box 157)
    - Mannheimer Memorial Fountain (St. Paul, MN), 1904-1906 (Box 157)
    - Marble Companies, 1901, 1905 (Box 157)
    - McKinley National Memorial (Canton, OH), 1904-1905 (Box 157)
    - Minnesota State Capital (St. Paul, MN), 1901-1933 (Box 158-175)
    - Montana Club (Helena, MT), 1903-1913 (Box 175-176)
    - Montana State University (Missoula and Bozeman, MT), 1916-1919 (Box 176)
    - Montana State Capitol (Butte, MT), undated (Box 176)
    - Monuments- First Division Memorial Association, 1922-1923 (Box 176)
    - Monuments- Jusserand Memorial (Washington, DC), 1932-1934 (Box 176)
    - Monuments- C.S. Pietro (Paris, France), 1917 (Box 176)
    - Monuments-Monument to the Preservation of Knowledge, 1933 (Box 176)
    - Monuments- Tennessee Memorial Competition (Nashville, TN), 1921-1922 (Box 176)
    - Mt. Vernon Shelter (Mt. Vernon, NY), 1922 (Box 177)
    - National State Savings Bank (Newark, NJ), 1909-1921 (Box 178-181)
    - New Business, 1899-1935 (Box 181-193)
    - New York County Lawyer's Association (New York, NY), 1927-1934 (Box 193-196)
    - New York Life Insurance Building (New York, NY), 1919-1934 (Box 196-221)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Bartow Station, NY, 1907-1911 (Box 221-222)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Baychester Station, NY, 1907 (Box 222)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Casanova Station, NY, 1907 (Box 222)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Hunt's Point Station, NY, 1907-1909 (Box 223)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Morris Park Station, NY, 1907-1911 (Box 223-224)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- New Haven Station, CT, 1906-1923 (Box 224-231)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Pelham Manor Station, NY, 1907-1909 (Box 231-232)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Port Morris Station, NY, 1907-1911 (Box 232-233)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Van Nest Station, NY, 1908 (Box 233)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- West Farms Station, NY, 1907 (Box 233)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Westchester Avenue Station, NY, 1907-1911 (Box 233)
    - Niagara Frontier Bridge (became Grand Island Bridge) (Niagara Falls, NY), 1929-1932 (Box 234)
    - Norfolk Savings Bank and Trust Co. (Norfolk, VA), Undated (Box 234)
    - Northwestern National Bank (Minneapolis, MN), 1919-1931 (Box 234)
    - Oberlin College (Oberlin, OH), 1904-1934 (Box 235-259)
    - 130 West 30th Street (New York, NY), 1927-1930 (Box 259-260)
    - Pan American Exposition (Buffalo, NY), 1901 (Box 260)
    - Peixollo, Flonair, 1901 (Box 260)
    - Prudential Life Insurance Company Bridges and Buildings (Newark, NJ), 1924-1934 (Box 260-280)
    - Read, George R., 1901-1902 (Box 280)
    - Realty Company Warehouse (Great Falls, MT), 1901-1905 (Box 280)
    - Realty Company Warehouse (Minneapolis, MN), 1899-1910 (Box 280)
    - Red Wing Auditorium (Red Wing, MN), 1902 (Box 281)
    - Ridgefield Fountain (Ridgefield, CT), 1914-1916 (Box 281)
    - Rodin Studios (New York, NY), 1916-1918 (Box 281-286)
    - Romeike, Henry, 1901-1905 (Box 286)
    - Roselawn Cemetery (Rose Town, MN), 1902-1904 (Box 286)
    - Sailor's Snug Harbor Apartments (New York, NY), 1922 (Box 286)
    - Saint John the Divine Episcopal Church (Moorhead, MN), Undated (Box 286)
    - Saint John's the Evangelist (St.Paul, MN), 1901-1902 (Box 286)
    - Saint Louis Art Museum (see Louisiana Purchase Exposition)
    - Saint Louis First National Bank (St. Louis, MO), 1919-1921 (Box 287)
    - Saint Louis Hotel (Duluth, MN), 1901-1919 (Box 287-289)
    - Saint Louis Public Library (St. Louis, MO), 1907-1921 (Box 289-303)
    - Saint Peter's Hospital (Helena, MT), 1908-1912 (Box 303)
    - Scheuer Building (Newark, NJ), 1904-1917 (Box 304-306)
    - Schiller Monument (St. Paul, MN), 1905-1906 (Box 306)
    - School of Industrial Arts (Trenton, NJ), 1909-1931 (Box 306-308)
    - Scott Fountain and Belle Isle Bridge (Detroit, MI), 1914-1932 (Box 308-314)
    - Scoville Manufacturing Company (Waterbury, CT), 1917-1924 (Box 314-315)
    - Sculptors' Letters, 1901-1905 (Box 315)
    - Seaside Sanatorium (Waterford, CT), 1930-1934 (Box 315-323)
    - Second Church of Christ Scientist (Milwaukee, WI), 1903 (Box 323)
    - Seliman & Meyer, 1901-1903 (Box 323)
    - Shattuck School (Faribault, MN), 1901-1922 (Box 323-324)
    - Soldiers and Sailors Memorial (Duluth, MN), 1915-1924 (Box 324-325)
    - Spaulding Building (Portland, OR), 1903-1923 (Box 325-328)
    - Spaulding Property (Oakland, CA), 1901 (Box 328)
    - State Savings Bank (Butte, MT), 1906-1909 (Box 328)
    - Stone, Carpenter & Wilson, 1903-1904 (Box 329)
    - Strong, Sturgis & Company, 1901-1902 (Box 329)
    - Suffolk Savings Bank (Boston, MA), 1903-1909 (Box 329-334)
    - Samuel Thomas Tomb (Tarrytown, NY), 1903-1907 (Box 335)
    - Samuel Thomas, Property, 1902-1903 (Box 335)
    - Thompson-Starrett Company, 1901-1904 (Box 335)
    - Union Central Life Insurance Building (Cincinnati, OH), 1906-1925 (Box 335-354)
    - Union Club (New York, NY), 1900-1907 (Box 354-370)
    - Union Engineering Building (St. Paul, MN), 1903 (Box 370)
    - Union Theological Seminary (New York, NY), 1906 (Box 370)
    - United Congregational Church (Bridgeport, CT), 1916-1924 (Box 370-371)
    - United States Army Supply Base (Brooklyn, New York), 1918-1932 (Box 371-380)
    - United States Chamber of Commerce (Washington, DC), 1919-1933 (Box 381-392)
    - United States Court House (New York, NY), 1930-1935 (Box 393-403)
    - United States Custom House (New York, NY), 1899-1934 (Box 404-439)
    - United States Department of Agriculture (Washington, DC), 1901-1905 (Box 439)
    - United States Legation Building (Ottawa, Canada), 1928-1934 (Box 439-442)
    - United States Supreme Court Building (Washington, D.C.), 1930-1936 (Box 442-463)
    - United States Treasury Department Annex (Washington, D.C.), 1917-1931 (Box 463-467)
    - University of Minnesota (Minneapolis, MN), 1906-1931 (Box 467-468)
    - University of Texas (Austin, TX), 1909-1927 (Box 469-481)
    - Vicksburg Monument (Vicksburg, MN), 1904-1906 (Box 481)
    - Ward Tomb (Newark, NJ), 1905-1913 (Box 482)
    - Ware, James E. & Sons, 1904 (Box 482)
    - Warehouse Cold Storage Project (St. Paul, MN), 1901-1904 (Box 482)
    - Warehouse Project (St. Paul, MN), 1902 (Box 482)
    - Washington DC Mall Preservation (Washington, DC), 1903-1904 (Box 482)
    - Washington State Capitol (Olympia, WA), 1893 (Box 482)
    - Waterbury Club (Waterbury, CT), 1914-1925 (Box 482-485)
    - Waterbury Municipal Building (Waterbury, CT), 1913-1920 (Box 485-494)
    - Waterbury National Bank (Waterbury, CT), 1918-1926 (Box 494-499)
    - Waterproofing Companies, 1901 (Box 499)
    - West Point Project (West Point, NY), 1903 (Box 499)
    - West Street Building (New York, NY), 1905-1933 (Box 499-502)
    - West Virginia State Capitol (Wheeling, WV), 1921-1952 (Box 503-524)
    - Western Press Clippings Bureau, 1901, 1905 (Box 524)
    - Williams Warehouse (New York, NY), 1927-1930 (Box 524-526)
    - Wisconsin State Capitol (Madison, WI), 1903-1907 (Box 526-527)
    - Woolworth Building (New York, NY), 1910-1933 (Box 528-565)
    - Woolworth Memorial Church (Great Bend, NY), 1912-1914 (Box 565)
    - Judge George B. Young Monument (Martha's Vineyard, MA), 1903-1907 (Box 565)
    - Projects Unclear, 1900-1936 (Box 565)
  - Subseries II: Bound Volumes
    This subseries contains all the volumes relating to Cass Gilbert's architectural projects. The volumes are mainly letterbooks containing outgoing copies of correspondence or books of specifications. Other volumes include records of contracts or financial ledgers. Many of these volumes are fragile and access is dependent upon the judgment of the print room staff.
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1929-1930 (Volume 1-3)
    - American Insurance Company Building, 1902-1921 (Volume 4-8)
    - Arkansas State Capitol, 1909-1912 (Volume 9-11)
    - Austin Nichols & Company, 1913-1916 (Volume 12-16)
    - Beverly Public Library, 1910-1914 (Volume 17)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank, 1916-1929 (Volume 18-22)
    - Broadway Chambers Building, 1898-1901 (Volume 23-26)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices, 1916-1920 (Volume 27-29)
    - Chase Memorial Dispensary, 1923-1924 (Volume 30)
    - Detroit Public Library, 1913-1922 (Volume 31-36)
    - Essex Country Courthouse, 1901-1907 (Volume 37-42)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis, 1921-1925 (Volume 43-46)
    - First Division Memorial, 1924-1935 (Volume 47)
    - Floranada Club, 1925-1926 (Volume 48)
    - G. Fox and Co. Department Store, 1917 (Volume 49-50)
    - Helena Hotel, 1912 (Volume 51)
    - Hotchkiss School, 1914-1930 (Volume 52-57)
    - Hudson River Bridge, 1926-1934 (Volume 58-60)
    - Interzone Building, 1923-1931 (Volume 61-64)
    - Ives Memorial Library, 1908-1911 (Volume 65-68)
    - James House, 1931-1932 (Volume 69)
    - Kill Van Kull Bridge, 1926-1934 (Volume 70-71)
    - Kinney Building, 1912-1931 (Volume 72-81)
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1901-1916 (Volume 82-84)
    - Minnesota State Capital, 1902-1907 (Volume 85-103)
    - Montana Club, 1904-1905 (Volume 104)
    - National State Savings Bank, 1910-1915 (Volume 105-107)
    - New York County Lawyer's Association, 1929 (Volume 108-110)
    - New York Life Insurance Building, 1924-1936 (Volume 111-125)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- Bartow Station, 1910-1918 (Volume 126)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Stations- New Haven Station, 1917-1919 (Volume 127-129)
    - Oberlin College, 1905-1930 (Volume 130-143)
    - 130 West 30th Street, 1927-1929 (Volume 144)